Okay guys, welcome to another video, in this video we will see the EDR, so next we will
call it as a next gen Antigura software, so endpoint detection and response so you can
see many jobs nowadays like MDR, EDR, XPR, everyone will be, everything will be working
under this ADL tool, so you have lot of tools like sofos, intercept tags and crowd strike
falcon, make a free ambition, trend micro have an EDR, idm has separate of EDR and
VMWare have carbon black and many of it does we have a collect cell there own EDR, so
many security providers they have a separate EDR for their environment, so many customers
will be using whatever the EDR is feasible for a customer they will be purchasing that
EDR and they release but there is a big difference between the anti-virus softwares
and EDRs when comparing to, so in anti-virus software so if you are downloading anything
it will detect the threat and it will be clearing out the threat right, so anti-virus
software has limited features comparing to EDRs like it will not detect it will not
work all the time, so if the detectors also very good knowledge they can able to bypass
many bypass using bypass anti-virus software using some scripts, it will be easily get
bypassed but EDRs is not like that, so EDR will be the next level, we have seen the
static engine dynamic engine and heuristic engine, so this all engines will be under the
endpoint detection and response EDR tool, as well as this EDR tool will have a artificial
intelligence and machine learning knowledge, it will detect live threat, so also we can
do some investigation related to the threat and we can do a live response, incident response
in the same EDR tool, okay, no don't worry about that, we can explore the EDR tool
completely in the next video, I explained the Microsoft Defender ATP EDR top to bottom
everything, so how we are doing the live response, how we are installing the agents and
what is the EDR and how the threats will be, they are how we need to investigate the
threats in EDR, okay, so the anti-virus software and EDRs are very different because
anti-virus software primarily detects known threat using the signature base detection, it
only focus on the data base, so that you will be getting the updates more time and many
of them are saying you may hear about that, you need to update the security software, because
security software updates will be having a latest hash value, so the hash value will be
updating in your bit different anti-virus software, so nothing about that, but if you see
about the EDR, detect known and unknown threat using the behavior analysis, so it will monitor
the behavior of the machine and if the behavior changes, if there is any root behavior
or any suspicious behavior it will monitor that and it will compare that analysis with
the ML machine learning and the artificial intelligence program, then it will conclude
it will be a benign, it will be a threat or it will be a false positive, okay, so it will
detect unknown threat also, okay, so there is no visibility in a real time, so which
was detected and so what was the scenario and all, but the EDR provides a very good
visibility, so which command line get executed and what was the end point which get detected
and so what the file file has, what's the process command line, everything will be there
in the EDR, so response capabilities, there is no live response in the anti-virus software
if you need to do an incident response, but EDR provides a live response, so we can
see that in the next video, okay, so don't worry about that and data collections, so it
will collect all the data for a foreign six analysis, okay, so the EDRs will collect all
the data from your machine and it will be saved in the cloud, so you can able to investigate
that, so you can investigate the data laterally, so if you want, so you can flag whether
there is a real threat or malicious false positive of going on, okay, so all the data will
be saved in the cloud, so you can easily take the data and you can investigate that,
but the traditional anti-virus software, it will not offer that kind of things, it will
not save your data into the cloud and the threat intel, so EDR has very good threat intel,
but the traditional anti-virus do not support the threat intals and all, okay, so we will
explore the Microsoft Defender ATP in the next video and we can see everything, but let
me show a few things, so this is the live response, if you will be taking in the EDRs,
okay, so you will be getting the live command and control console, so you can command
whatever you want, okay, so it will be like that, so connections for the connections you
can see, okay, so you can see all the files which will be under the programs or any download
folders, so no problem, we will see everything in the next video, see you guys, bye